<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.blitzfc.qbz</id>
  <name>QBZ</name>
  <summary>Hi-fi music player for Qobuz</summary>
  <description>
    <p>
      QBZ is a native Qobuz client for Linux focused on reliable hi-res playback and desktop integration.
    </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Bit-perfect playback up to 24-bit/192kHz</li>
      <li>PipeWire and PulseAudio audio output</li>
      <li>DAC routing and exclusive mode support</li>
      <li>Local music library with offline playback</li>
      <li>Immersive and miniplayer display modes</li>
      <li>Artist blacklist for personalized listening</li>
      <li>MPRIS integration for desktop media controls</li>
      <li>Last.fm and ListenBrainz scrobbling</li>
      <li>Plex library integration</li>
      <li>Direct streaming or smart cache playback</li>
      <li>Highly customizable interface and behavior</li>
    </ul>
  </description>
  <developer id="com.blitzfc">
    <name>QBZ Contributors</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://github.com/vicrodh/qbz</url>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/vicrodh/qbz/issues</url>
  <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/vicrodh/qbz</url>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>MIT</project_license>
  <branding>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#2b6cb0</color>
    <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#63b3ed</color>
  </branding>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.blitzfc.qbz.desktop</launchable>
  <provides>
    <binary>qbz</binary>
  </provides>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption xml:lang="en">Home and discovery view</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vicrodh/qbz/cff32e5da726719b983770c7f4c2ff52bb51e14d/packaging/flatpak/screenshots/home-discover.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption xml:lang="en">Immersive cover flow mode</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vicrodh/qbz/cff32e5da726719b983770c7f4c2ff52bb51e14d/packaging/flatpak/screenshots/immersive-cover-flow.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <caption xml:lang="en">Local library view</caption>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/vicrodh/qbz/cff32e5da726719b983770c7f4c2ff52bb51e14d/packaging/flatpak/screenshots/local-library.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.2.1" date="2026-03-25">
      <description>
        <p>Resilience: exponential backoff retry (1s/2s/4s) with quality fallback when Qobuz servers return 504s. User preference modal for retry behavior (ask/always fallback/always skip), persisted in settings. Degraded service indicator with 5-minute auto-clear. Manual network check button. macOS port foundation (gated backends, native title bar, CI workflow). Offline mode improvements (last known profile restore, dismissible banner, network folders). WebKitGTK 2.50+ image flicker fix. Hybrid Intel+NVIDIA compositing fix. QConnect fixes for queue_version tolerance and ALSA volume control. i18n: hardcoded strings replaced in SearchView and PlaylistDetailView. Security: aws-lc-sys 0.39.0, rustls-webpki 0.103.10.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2026-03-19">
      <description>
        <p>Qobuz Connect: multi-device playback with renderer and controller mode, server-authoritative queue sync, and bidirectional transport controls. Linebed 3D terrain visualizer with 4096-point FFT. Qobuz playlist follow/unfollow with native API sync. Audio settings sync overhaul fixing exclusive mode with QConnect. Volume lock for ALSA Direct hw:. HiFi Wizard real DAC sample rate detection. MuPDF 0.6 restoring booklet viewer. Offline mode button on network error screen. KWin SSD hack removed. PipeWire rate switch verification with retry. Help tooltips on bit-perfect settings. 185 commits.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.20" date="2026-03-11">
      <description>
        <p>Fix startup crash on Debian sid and Fedora (missing libjpeg). Fix partial cover art in AppImage. Fix track number display for compilations and box sets. Fix PipeWire bit-perfect stream match rule in Hi-Fi Wizard. Security update for quinn-proto. Test fixes for cross-distro builds.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.19" date="2026-03-09">
      <description>
        <p>Scene Discovery: explore artists from the same city or musical scene. Redesigned Home with 3 Discovery Tabs (Home, Editor's Picks, For You) with personalized radio stations, spotlight artist, and genre filtering. Neon visualizers (Laser, Tunnel, Comet) with album art color extraction. In-app PDF booklet viewer. Audio engine upgrade to rodio 0.22 with ALSA gapless playback. Security hardening and stability fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.18" date="2026-02-26">
      <description>
        <p>Miniplayer window with compact and micro surfaces. OAuth browser login for new Qobuz auth flow. Window size persistence, HiDPI scaling fix, and artist image context menus.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.16" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>OAuth browser authentication, window size persistence, HiDPI scaling fix for all backends, and login flow improvements.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.15" date="2026-02-23">
      <description>
        <p>Multi-select tracks across all views with bulk queue and playlist actions. Scroll position now scoped per item and expires after one hour.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.11" date="2026-02-10">
      <description>
        <p>Discover browse pages for albums and playlists, localized playlist tags, preserved Qobuz artwork on playlist copy, and UI fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.9" date="2026-02-07">
      <description>
        <p>Maintenance release: faster Home view, playback auto-resume after settings change, playlist import improvements, and bug fixes.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.1.8" date="2026-01-25">
      <description>
        <p>Major release: genre filtering, playlist suggestions, immersive player, DAC wizard, key bindings, artist blacklist.</p>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
